Rangga Perkasa Aprili Sugiyanto Software Engineer

Tulungagung, Indonesia | +6281249888836 | ranggaperkasa822@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/rangga-perkasa-aprili-sugiyanto-4063a41b4/ | https://github.com/RanggaPerkasaAS

SUMMARY

Hello, I am a graduate of Telkom Malang Vocational School majoring in Software Engineering who is currently studying at Bina Nusantara University majoring in Information Systems. I master the Javascript programming language and usually use the NodeJS and Express frameworks.

I have 1 year of work experience in SIMTEK (Simbiotik Innovation Technology) in the field of Software Developer. As a software developer there, I worked on several projects, namely developing the company's website using Laravel, developing the frontend (Next JS) and backend (Nest JS) of the Naga Exchange application Dashboard, and most recently being the Backend Developer of the hospital Dashboard project using Express JS.

In 2021, I have internship experience at PT Artha Elektronika (EzyPay) for 3 months as a software engineer there I helped develop the web from the utter academy with the PHP programming language and the Codelgniter framework

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT Simbiotik Innovation Technology (SIMTEK) – Tangerang, Banten, Indonesia Software Engineer (August 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2023) Fulltime

- Develop simtek websites using the Laravel framework.
- Develop dashboard website for Naga Exchange application admin using Next JS for Frontend and Nest JS for Backend.
- Develop the backend of the Siloam Hospital dashboard website for admin using Express.

PT Artha Elektronika (EzyPay) – Malang, Indonesia

Software Engineer (JULY 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021) Internship

- Help develop 5 pages of the Utter Academy website using PHP language, and Codelgniter framework
- Re-design UI UX of the utter academy course page

EDUCATION

BINA NUSANTARA UNIVERSITY ONLINE LEARNING (2023 - present)

Majoring in Information Systems

SMK TELKOM MALANG (2019 - 2022)

Vocational High School of Software Engineering

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

Paskibra SMK TELKOM MALANG

Co - Leader (December 2020 - December 2021)

- During my tenure as Co-Leader, I was often a presenter at weekly forum activities and became a regular trainer for weekly training
- managed to create a combined training event with other extracurriculars

HARD SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Java
- PHP
- Nest Js
- Next Js

- Node Js
- React Js
- MySQL
- Postgree
- HTML & CSS

SOFT SKILLS

- High Loyalty
- Responsible
- Teamwork

- Critical Thinking
- Honest

PROJECT

Siloam Admin Dashboard

Express (August 2023 - present)

- Creating API using Express
- In this project using Postgree as a database.

Naga Exchange Admin Dashboard

Next JS & Nest JS (January 2023 – July 2023)

- Creating Dashboard website for Naga Exchange application admin using Next JS.
- Creating API using Nest JS
- In this project using Postgree as a database.

Simtek Website

Laravel (August 2022 – September 2022)

- Creating Website simtek using Laravel framewok
- In this projet I use MYSQL as a database

Web Admin Laundry

NodeJS & ReactJS (November 2020 - February 2021)

- Creating API and CRUD using NodeJS framework
- Make frontend from laundry with ReactJs framework
- In this project I use MYSQL as the database

PYP Project Show Case Niaga

ReactJS (JUNE 2021)

• Creating a website showcase of group business ideas with the ReactJS framework

Utter Academy Website

CODEIGNITER (JULY 2021 – SEPTEMBER 2021)

- Internship project to develop 5 page the utter academy website using the PHP programming language and the Codelgniter framework
- Re-design UI UX of the utter academy course page

Backend Toko

NodeJS (April 2021)

• Creating API and CRUD using NodeJS framework

Project Work SMK TELKOM MALANG

PHP (April 2020)

- Create a bookstore and car rental CRUD website with the PHP programming language.
- In this project I use MYSQL as the database.

CERTIFICATE

Microsoft Technology Associate

Introduction to Programming using JavaScript (December 2021)